A Finding Aid to the Thomas Carr Howe papers, 1932-1984, in the Archives of American Art AAA.howethom
Archives of American Art
Thomas Carr Howe papers
1932-1984
AAA.howethom
Archives of American Art
4.4 Linear feet
The Thomas Carr Howe papers measure 4.4 linear feet and date from 1932 to 1984. Howe was director of the California Palace of the Legion of Honor in San Francisco for nearly 40 years, and he served as one of the Monuments Men in the Monuments, Fine Art and Archives (MFAA) Section of the U.S. Army during World War II. The collection documents Howe's MFAA work in Germany and Austria locating and recovering cultural artifacts and artwork stolen by the Nazis. There is significant correspondence with friends and colleagues, as well as fellow Monuments Men such as Samson Lane Faison, Edith Standen, and George Stout. The papers also includes reports, inventories of stolen artwork, maps, annotated photographs, a scrapbook, and photographs. The papers also document Howe's later work at the California Palace of the Legion of Honor.
Howe, Thomas Carr
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Thomas Carr Howe donated his papers to the Archives of American Art in multiple installments from 1979 to 1982.
Related Material
Among the holdings of the Archives of American are the papers of several additional members of the U. S. Army MFAA section. There is an oral history interview with Thomas Carr Howe and Robert Neuhaus conducted by Paul Karlstrom and Peter Fairbanks on September 26, 1987 and another with Howe conducted by Paul Karlstrom on June 2-3, 1976.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Thomas Carr Howe, Jr. (1904-1994) served as the director of the California Palace of the Legion of Honor in San Francisco for nearly four decades and, during World War II, as an officer in the U.S. Army's Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives unit assisting with locating, recovering, and restituting cultural objects and artwork stolen by the Nazis.
Howe was born in Kokomo, Indiana in 1904. He studied at Harvard University where he received his bachelor's and master's degrees. Howe was the assistant director of the California Palace of the Legion of Honor in San Francisco from 1931-1939 and director from 1939-1968. Howe was also the art commissioner for the San Francisco Golden Gate International Exposition (1939-1940) for which he organized an exhibition showcasing Mexican muralists.
During World War II, Howe joined the U.S. army and served from 1945 to 1946 in Germany and Austria. He began as a naval lieutenant but was soon assigned to serve in the Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives (MFAA) section. Howe reported to Lieutenant Commander George Stout at Wiesbaden, and was later promoted to Lieutenant Commander and Deputy Chief of the MFAA at Frankfurt. During his service as one of the "Monuments Men" Howe located hidden and recovered large repositories of cultural objects and works of art stolen by the Nazis. He also helped with the restitution effort. At the Altaussee salt mines in Austria, Howe helped salvage a large cache of stolen artwork that included Michelangelo's Madonna and Child and the Ghent Altarpiece or The Adoration of the Mystic Lamb by Hubert and Jan van Eyck, Vermeer's The Artists Studio, and the Rothschild family jewels. Howe later described his wartime work in his book Salt Mines and Castles: The Discovery and Restitution of Looted European Art (1946).
Howe resumed his position as the director of the California Palace of the Legion on Honor after the war, a position he held until his retirement in 1968. Through his career as a prominent art director, Howe was close with many American and international museum professionals, collectors and socialites. Friends and colleagues include Agnes Mongan and Paul Sachs (both former directors of Harvard's Fogg Museum), Whitney Warren, and Gerda and Hans-Erich Von Schmidt auf Altenstadt.
For his wartime service as a Monuments Men, Howe was honored with the Chevalier of the French Legion of Honor and the Officier of the Dutch Order of Orange-Nassau in 1946. At the request of the federal government, Howe also later served as the Cultural Affairs Advisor to the High Commissioner of Germany from 1950-1951, during which time he returned to Germany with S. Lane Faison, another MFAA official, to assist with closing the central collecting points where the recovered artworks has been held for restitution. From 1960-1968, Howe was a member of the Fine Arts Committee for The White House and he continued to serve on numerous panels and commissions as an art advisor.
Howe married Francesca Deering. Together they had one daughter Francesca.
Scope and Content Note
The Thomas Carr Howe papers measure 4.4 linear feet and date from 1932 to 1984. Howe was director of the California Palace of the Legion of Honor in San Francisco for nearly 40 years, and he served as one of the Monuments Men in the Monuments, Fine Art and Archives (MFAA) Section of the U.S. Army during World War II. The collection documents Howe's MFAA work in Germany and Austria locating and recovering cultural artifacts and artwork stolen by the Nazis. There is significant correspondence with friends and colleagues, as well as fellow Monuments Men such as Samson Lane Faison, Edith Standen, and George Stout. The papers also includes reports, inventories of stolen artwork, maps, annotated photographs, a scrapbook, and photographs. The papers also document Howe's later work at the California Palace of the Legion of Honor.
Biographical materials include articles and memorial tributes for Howe's father and grandfather, a short autobiography and resume, and the certificate for the copyright to his book.
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence, the most voluminous of which are letters from Monuments Men S. Lane Faison, Patrick J. Kelleher, Andrew C. Ritchie, Edith Standen, George Stout, Marcelle Minet, Rose Valland, James Rorimer, and others. Additional correspondents include friends and colleagues such as Bernard Berenson, Hume Cronyn, Paul Mills, Christopher Forbes, Margaret Mallory, William A. McGonagle, and Otto Wittman, among many others
Writings include a brief summary of Howe's book Salt Mines and Castles and a sound cassette of his lecture about the book. Project, membership and travel files are primarily associated with his professional work at the California Palace of the Legion of Honor and include documentation of member art trips, a feasibility study for merging the California Palace of the Legion of Honor with the M. H. de Young Memorial Museum, and a membership list of the Bohemian Club.
The Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives (MFAA) Records and Looted Inventories series contain many records relating to Howe's military service as a Monuments Man. There are several inventory records which contain lists of the contents of Hermann Göring's collection of looted artwork, artwork destroyed in the Flak towers fire in Berlin, and artwork held at several of the central collecting points, though mostly at Weisbaden. There is also a small fold out map of the Altausse salt mines; a U.S. government issued manual of maps marking important cultural monuments and artwork in Germany; a book of U.S. government regulations pertaining to the MFAA section; a government information bulletin; and several official status reports and published U.S. government reports about art looting investigations and safeguarding cultural property.
Professional files consist of papers relating to Howe's job as the director of the California Palace of the Legion of Honor and art trips he organized. Documents include a survey of Los Angeles museum curator salaries, a questionnaire about Howe's work as a museum director, and a membership list of Bohemian Club artists. The bulk of the travel papers are itineraries.
The photographs are divided into two subseries: MFAA Section images and personal photographs. The Monuments Men subseries includes photographs documenting bomb damage to cultural monuments in various countries, though mainly Germany; U.S. soldiers transporting recovered artwork such as Michelangelo's Madonna and Child from the Altaussee salt mines in Austria, and other looted art repositories such as Neuschwanstein Castle and Berchtesgaden in Germany; Weisbaden and Munich collecting points; and art recovery of The Adoration of the Mystic Lamb by Hubert and Jan van Eyck. There are many photographs of the Monuments Men including Thomas Carr Howe, George Stout, Stephen Kovalyak, Lamont Moore, Patrick J. Kelleher, Edith Standen, and Rose Valland. Personal photographs consists of portraits of Howe and photographs of events, mostly formal dinners and parties.
Printed materials are clippings, postcards, fundraising pamphlets, essays, and memorial tributes for colleagues.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 10 series:
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1934-1955, 1974 (Box 1; 6 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1932-1984 (Box 1-3; 2.1 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings, circa 1946 (Box 3; 2 folders)
Series 4: Professional Files, circa 1945-1975 (Box 3, 5; 0.3 linear feet folders)
Series 5: Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Records and Looted Inventories, circa 1942-1950 (Box 3, 5, OV 6; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 6: Photographs, 1938-1970 (Box 3-5; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 7: Scrapbook, 1936-1948 (Box 4; 0.1 linear feet)
Series 8: Printed Materials, 1934-1980 (Box 4; 0.4 linear feet)
Allied Forces.--Supreme Headquarters.--Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Section; Berenson, Bernard, 1865-1959; Bohemian Club (San Francisco, Calif.); California Palace of the Legion of Honor; Cronyn, Hume; Faison, S. Lane (Samson Lane), 1907-2006; Göring, Hermann, 1893-1946; Hancock, Walker Kirtland, 1901-; Kelleher, Patrick J. (Patrick Joseph), 1917-; M.H. De Young Memorial Museum; Mallory, Margaret, 1911-1998; Mills, Paul Chadbourne, 1924-; Moore, Lamont; Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff; Rorimer, James J. (James Joseph), 1905-1966; Standen, Edith Appleton; Stout, George L. (George Leslie); United States.--Army.--Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Section; Valland, Rose; Wittmann, Otto, 1911-2001; Art thefts--Germany--History--20th century; Art treasures in war--France; Art treasures in war--Germany; Arts administrators--California--San Francisco; Cultural property--Protection--Europe--History--20th century; Museum directors--California--San Francisco; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Sound recordings; World War, 1939-1945--Art and the war; World War, 1939-1945--Confiscations and contributions--Germany; World War, 1939-1945--Destruction and pillage--Europe
- Biographical Materials, 1974; 1934-1955; Series 1; 6 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes a short autobiographical sketch that Howe wrote when he was 30; obituaries and news clippings for Howe's father Thomas Carr Howe; a scholarship announcement with congratulations; the copyright certificate for Salt Mines and Castles; and an article about Addison F. Armstrong, Howe's maternal grandfather; and a resume.
  - Autobiographical Sketch, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Thomas Carr Howe, Sr., Obituaries and News Clippings, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scholarship Announcement and Congratulations, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Copyright Certificate, 1952; 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Addison F. Armstrong Article, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Resume, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1932-1984; Series 2; 2.1 Linear feet Box 1-3
  This series contains personal and professional correspondence. Howe wrote brief descriptions identifying the correspondent, such as the person's job or relationship, on many of the letters. Correspondence with individuals who wrote infrequently is arranged chronologically. Correspondence with friends and colleagues, as well as letters written by prominent figures in the art world, such as artists and historians, are separated and arranged alphabetically. Also found here is correspondence from his post-war work as the Cultural Affairs Advisor to the U.S. High Commissioner of Germany.
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  Subseries 2.1: Chronological Correspondence, 1932-1942, 1946-1953, 1957-1984
  Subseries 2.2: Cultural Affairs Advisor, 1948-1952
  Subseries 2.3: Alphabetical Correspondence, 1933-1983
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1932-1984; 2.1:
    This subseries consists of personal and professional letters between Howe and his friends and colleagues. Correspondents include the Director of the Metropolitan Museum of Art Francis Henry Taylor, Baroness Phillippe de Rothschild, and Chairman of the Smithsonian Art Commission Charles H. Sawyer.
    Due to the small number of letters from these individuals, separate folders were not created for each person and the letters were left in the chronological order in which they were found.
    The letters are arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by correspondent within each year.
    - A-Z, 1932-1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - A-Z, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - A-Z, 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - A-Z, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - A-Z, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - A-Z, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - A-Z, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - A-Z, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - A-Z, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - A-Z, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - A-Z, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - A-Z, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - A-G, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - H-Z, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - A-Z, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - A-Z, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - A-N, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - O-Z, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - A-Z, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - A-Z, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - A-Z, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - A-Z, 1983-1984; 1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cultural Affairs Advisor to the U.S. High Commissioner of Germany, 1948-1952; 2.2:
    After World War II, the U.S. State Department requested Howe to take a leave of absence as art director of the California Palace of the Legion of Honor in order to continue the recovery and repatriation of looted artworks in Europe. These letters are from Howe's time as the Cultural Affairs Advisor to the U.S. High Commissioner of Germany which represented the U.S. Government in Germany with regards to economic affairs.
    Howe and fellow Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives officer S. Lane Faison directed the closing of the Collecting Points for the recovered artworks. The letters in this subseries are professional letters dealing with Howe's responsibilities. The letters often include attachments of memorandums and reports.
    - Cultural Affairs Advisor, 1949 June-1950 December (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Cultural Affairs Advisor, 1951 January-March (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Cultural Affairs Advisor, 1951 June-July (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Cultural Affairs Advisor, 1951 April-May (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Cultural Affairs Advisor, 1951 August-1952 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Cultural Affairs Advisor Miscellaneous, circa 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Alphabetical Correspondence, 1933-1983; 2.3:
    This subseries includes the letters of Howe's friends, colleagues, fellow Monuments Men, and two relatives (his sister and cousin). Among the Monuments Men correspondents are: S. Lane Faison, P.J. Kelleher, Lamont Moore, Andrew C. Ritchie, James Rorimer, Edith Standen, George Stout, and Rose Valland. There are also letters from prominent members of the art world such as museum directors, gallery owners, artists, curators and collectors including Bernard Berenson, Hume Cronyn, Christopher Forbes, Paul Mills, Agnes Mongan, Marcelle Minet, Margaret Mallory, William McGonagle, Paul Sachs and Whitney Warren. Howe often wrote comments on the letters identifying the correspondent.
    There are also a few folders with professional correspondence related to Howe's job as the director of the Californian Palace of the Legion of Honor and his membership in various arts organizations and committees.
    Letters are arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - Bartlett, Fred, 1975-1977; 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Beaton, Cecil, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      One brief letter.
    - Berenson, Bernard, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Bohemian Club, 1961-1977 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - California Palace of the Legion of Honor, 1958-1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Cannon, Ernestine, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Cheek, Leslie, 1958-1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Citation for the Chevalier of the French Legion of Honor, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Clary, Princess Lidi, 1959-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Cronyn, Hume, 1975 December (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Cunningham, Charles C., 1979; 1971-1975; 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Curtis, Charles and Margaret, 1958-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dayton, Alan W., 1958; 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - de Vries, A. B., 1960-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Faison, S. Lane, 1949-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Faison, S. Lane, 1961-1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Feray, Jean, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Fine Arts Committee for the White House, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Forbes, Christopher, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Foster, James W., 1961-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Grier, Harry D. M., 1964-1966; 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Heinrich, Theodore A., 1946-1952; 1962-1966; 1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hesse: Princess Margaret of Hesse, 1953-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Signs the letters as Peg.
    - Howe, Charlotte B., 1958-1959; 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Thomas Carr Howe's sister.
    - Howe, Lucia, 1951; 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Thomas Carr Howe's cousin.
    - Imperial War Museum, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Recognition and thanks for copy of Salt Mines and Castles give by Howe to the Imperial War Museum.
    - Kelleher, Patrick Joe, 1970-1977; 1946-1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Kennedy, John F., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      One letter.
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1946-1948; 1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Kovalyak, Stephen, 1949-1950; 1975; 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - LaFarge, Bancel, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Lazard, Esther, 1950-1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Lesley, Everett Parker, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Loudon, John and Mary, 1958-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Mallory, Margaret, 1960-1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Malone, Lee, 1960; 1958 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - McBaine, Jane Neylan, 1958-1975 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - McGonagle, William A., 1966-1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - McIlhenny, Henry, 1951-1952; 1963-1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Mifflin, John, 1958-1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Mills, Paul C., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Minet, Marcelle, 1947-1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Minis, A., Jr., 1967; 1975; 1979 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Mognan, Agnes, 1933-1939; 1951-1979 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Moore, Lamont, 1979; 1975; 1965; 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Morley, Grace, 1958-1971 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Nipper, Clara, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Pleydell-Bouverie, David, 1951-1970 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Post, Jimmy J., 1971; 1958; 1975 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Ranneft, J. E. Meijer, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Letter referencing Howe's Officer in the Order of Orange-Nassau award.
    - Rathbone, Perry T., 1961-1978 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Reagan, Ronald, 1973; 1970; (2 letters.) (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Ritchie, Andrew and Jane, 1950-1979 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Roberts, Isabel and Laurance, 1953-1979 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Rorimer, James, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Sachs, Paul, 1934-1950; 1963-1971 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Smith, Howard Ross, 1958-1975 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Smyth, Craig Hugh, 1946-1977 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Spreckels, Adolph B., 1963-1968; 1935; 1949-1953 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Standen, Elizabeth, 1979; 1946-1952 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Stout, George, 1946; 1961-1977 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Sullivan, Mary, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Valland, Rose, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - von Schimdt, J.E.G. ("Hans-Erich") and Gerda, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - von Schimdt, J.E.G. ("Hans-Erich") and Gerda, 1953-1979 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Warburg, Edward M. M. and Mary, 1949-1978; 1933-1937 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Warren, Whitney, 1952-1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - White, Ian McKibben, 1966-1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Witt, Sir John, 1958-1978; 1948; 1932-1934 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Wittman, Otto, 1966-1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, 1950-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Writings, circa 1946; Series 3; 2 Folders Box 3
  This series includes a short summary by Howe of Salt Mines and Castles: Postwar Recovery of Looted Masterpieces and a cassette tape of a question and answer session with Howe about the book.
  - Salt Mines and Castles Summary, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Sound Cassette of Salt Mines and Castles Lecture, circa 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Professional Files, circa 1945-1975; Series 4; 0.3 Linear feet Box 3, 5
  Scattered professional files document some of Howe's work as the Director of the California Palace of the Legion of Honor and a few international art tours he organized. A few trips were organized in conjunction with the California Palace of the Legion of Honor and others were sponsored by the Museum Society, presumably the De Young Museum Society of San Francisco. Most of the records are copies of itineraries.
  This series also includes a survey of Los Angeles museum curator Salaries which Howe used to request a raise for his art director position at the California Palace of the Legion of Honor (CPLH); a membership list of Bohemian Club artists; and a Municipal Executive Employees Standardization Committee questionnaire about Howe's responsibilities as the CPLH director.
  - Survey of Los Angeles Museum Curator Salaries, circa 1945 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Municipal Executive Employees Association Standardization Committee Questionnaire, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Baroque Tour, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Zurich-Vienna Museum Trip, circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bohemian Club Artists Membership List, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Study for M.H. de Young Memorial Museum and California Palace of the Legion of Honor Merger, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Museum Trip to Holland and Belgium, 1975; 1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Austria and Munich Trip, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Belgian-Dutch Museum Trip, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Museum Trip to France, circa 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Oversized material housed in Box 5, Folder 1.
  - Germany and Austria Museum Trip, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Oversized French Magazine from Box 3, Folder 18, circa 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Records and Looted Art Inventories, circa 1942-1950; Series 5; 0.3 Linear feet Box 3, 5, OV 6
  This series includes inventories of looted art, official and published reports, and printed materials such as maps, bulletins, and a book of government regulations all related to Howe's work in the Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Section.
  Subseries 5.1: Looted Art Inventories, circa 1942-1950
  Subseries 5.2: Reports, 1944-1949
  Subseries 5.3: Printed Materials, 1944-1947
  - Looted Art Inventories, circa 1942-1950; 5.1:
    The subseries contains inventories of artwork from various sources: photostatic copies of German inventories of artwork; inventories of Hermann Göring's Art Collection which includes lists of paintings, sculptures, tapestries, furniture and other valuables found in a building in Unterstein, Germany; inventories and transportation of artwork recovered from Berchtesgaden, Germany and Altaussee, Austria, and other locations; inventories of recovered artwork at Weisbaden (bulk) and Munich Central Collecting Points; and an inventory of artwork lost in the Flak Towers fires in Berlin, Germany.
    - German Inventories of Art, circa 1942-1950 (Box 3, Folder 20)